#大家好
Hi everyone!
#你看這個門 那個年事已高喔 這個門
Look at the gate! It's aged, the gate.
#它已經快七八年啦
It has been here for almost eight years now.
#下面都爛掉啦
The lower part is already broken.
#如果不修好的話那個狗老是往外面跑
It needs to be fixed. Or the dogs are always running way.
#會被那個 會被那 那些 小野狗啊
They'll, they'll be, be abducted,
#把它們拐跑的
by the wild doggies.
#等下我把它修一下
I'll fix it today.
#要用這個鐵綫紥一下
How about tying it with iron wire?
#紥起來
Tie it up.
#我要去買一點 買一點鐵綫回來
I'll buy some, buy some iron wire.
#要不然 要不然修不了 又沒有電焊機
Otherwise, otherwise, it can't be fixed. We don't have a welding machine here.
#你看這個母狗 它現在很老實哦 待在家裡不走啦 (註︰我用"mother"是想擬人一點，畢竟她真的是小狗的娘)
Look at the mother. She is very mature now and is just staying at home all the time.
#你看 它現在好溫順哦
Look! She is now very nice and gentle.
#給你按按摩
Give you a massage.
#剛好買了鐵綫回來
I'm just back with the iron wire.
#這個鐵綫很便宜呀
It's really cheap.
#這麼多才六塊錢
This whole bunch costs me only 6 RMB.
#啊 爛成這樣
Ah! What a mess!
#這樣揅不多就很穩了
It should be quite stable now.
#可以
Alright!
#這門條好就可以啦
So long as the gate is fixed.
#不然的話讓狗跑出去啦
Otherwise the dogs are running away.
#剛剛好
Perfect!
#這個小黑
The Blacky,
#很喜歡往這個洞裡面鑽 那麼小它都鑽的[SIC]過去
always squeezes through this hole. I simply don't know how she can squeeze through such a small hole.
#我把它封起來
I'll block it.
#不要讓它跑出去啦
I'm not letting her run away.
#這樣小黑就跑不出去啦
Then Blacky will no longer have any chance.
#我就不相信 那麼一點點它能鑽的[SIC]出去
The hole is too small for her now. She can't make it.
#好啦
Alright!
#只要跑不出去就行啦 那小狗
It's fine so long as they can't run away, I mean the doggies.